神经氨酸酶抑制剂...  神经氨酸酶抑制剂...
neuraminidase inhibitor...Neuraminidase inhibitor...
神经氨酸酶抑制剂...
Neuraminidase inhibitor...
听说你要去下外世界?
heard you're going off-world?
是的  我去协助一次复诊任务
i'm assisting with a medical follow-up
是在m33-985星球
On m33-985, yes.
和凯勒一起
with keller.
没错
right again.
在你休息的是时候
on your day off.
怎么了  我就不能在休息日去下外世界么
what, I can't go off-world in my free time?
可以  可以  你请便
no, no, go ahead.
我只是奇怪你啥时这么勤快
I just think it's odd that you're volunteering
在休息日自愿参与爱心任务
For goodwill missions on your day off.
我已不是以前的我了
well, I'm turning over a new leaf.
而是一个充满爱心温文尔雅的罗德尼·麦凯
It's a whole new kinder, gentler rodney mckay.
你来了
oh, there you are.
准备好了吗
You all set?
你也要来  是吗
you coming too, are you?
若楠说也来帮忙
yeah, ronon offered to help out, too,
我想多多益善  不是很好吗
So I just thought, you know, the more the merrier, right?
有问题吗
is there a problem?
没有  没有  没问题
no, no, no, just, I was...no, it's nothing.
好吧
okay.
查克  拨通星门  出发
Uh... go ahead and dial, chuck.
我来拿这个
i got this.
我拿得动的  我来拿这个
I'm good, I got it, I got it.
你要提这个?
I'm good. you want it?
你就提这个吧  我拿...
You take that, I got...
我拿我自己的东西
My own stuff I'll bring.
我们今天要治疗的病人
so, the people we're seeing today,
只要和他没有身体接触
As long as you avoid any physical contact,
应该就没事
You should be fine.
这病看起来不像是空气传播型的
The contagion doesn't seem to be airborne.
这里的人又得什么病了
what's wrong with these people again?
是一种类似地球上流感的病
it's a disease similar to one on earth Called influenza.
正在这村庄蔓延
It's been spreading throughout the village.
虽然不是什么大问题
Not too severe a strain,
但足以引起村民的恐慌
But enough to put a scare into them.
这孩子也得了
he's caught it, too.
情况怎么样
will he be all right?
烧得不重  多休息  多喝水
his fever's mild,so, plenty of rest, lots of fluids,
他就会好起来的
And he should be fine.
我会开点药
I'm also going to prescribe some medicine...
神经氨酸酶抑制剂?
oh, a neuraminidase inhibitor?
你不错啊
very good.
艾伦  我能不能给你也检查下
Can I have a look at you too, erran,
以防万一
Just to be on the safe side?
伙计们  你们能回避下吗
uh, do you guys mind giving us some privacy?
我知道这儿旁边有家小酒馆
I think there's a tavern close by.
你们为什么不去那吃点中饭
Why don't you go get some lunch?
你想要...  好的
You want to... sure.
你怎么了  不好吃?
what's the matter, you don't like it?
我说  你不必来这里的
you know, you don't have to be here.
在亚特兰蒂斯你一定还有很多事要干
I'm sure you got plenty of stuff To do back on atlantis.
事实上  我空闲的很
oddly enough, I don't, actually.
如果你要回去
But if you need to get back, then
不  我在这很好
no, I'm good.
你当然没事了
of course you are
你认为她们检查好了吗
you think we've given them enough time?
我可不希望在她们检查的时候
I don't want to interrupt
打扰她们
In the middle of medical... stuff.
凯勒医生检查好了吗
hi. um... is dr. keller done?
她没和你们在一起?
she's not with you?
她看完病后  就离开了
She finished with us, then left.
她说过和你们在小酒馆碰头的
Said she was going to join you at the tavern.
好的  谢了
oh. right. very good. thanks.
珍妮弗
jennifer?
jennifer!
珍妮弗  我是罗德尼  你能听见吗
jennifer, it's rodney, do you read me?
珍妮弗
jennifer!
凯勒医生  请回话
dr. keller, please respond.
要么她的无线电失灵了
well, either her radio isn't working,
要么她关掉了
Or she's turned it off.
她不会关掉无线电的
she wouldn't do that.
那她发生什么事了
then what happened to her?
有发现什么吗
anything?
我查看了街道  没人看见过她
I've checked down the street, no one seeing her
失踪了
she is vanished
没道理啊  她不会就这样带着东西走了
that doesn't make sense. she wouldn't take off the facility sourse going
除非有人把她绑走了
or unless someone took her against her will
你去星门那
mabe you should go back to the gate
无线电联系总部请求支援
Radio atlantis for help.
也许你说的对
maybe you're right.
我呆在这儿
i'll stay here
查看下整个村子
And check the entire village.
你是谁
who are you?
如果你乖乖的  我就不用打晕你
if you'd stop struggling, I wouldn't have to stun you.
你想要什么
what do you want from me?
闭嘴
and stop asking questions.
我只想知道你为什么绑架我
i just want to know why you kidnapped me.
你是怎么把我带离村子的
How did you take me from the village?
我都不记得...
I don't even remember...
很好
good.
我们出发
let's go.
麦凯
mckay?
收到  说吧
yeah, go ahead.
我在村子外发现了脚印
i got some footprints outside the village.
是珍妮弗的吗
jennifer's?
百分百亚特兰蒂斯的步子
standard atlantis tread.
还有其他人的脚印
But there's someone with her.
比较大
Bigger prints.
和我的脚印差不多
Like my size.
看起来有过挣扎的迹象
Looks like there was a struggle.
该死
oh... dammit.
奇怪的是
weird thing is...
脚印就这么凭空出现在这里
It's like they just appeared out of nowhere.
凭空出现  什么意思
what do you mean, nowhere?
我是说这里和村子之间
i mean there's nothing at all
一个脚印也没有
Between here and the village.
就这么在这凭空出现
Then they just appear,
好像从天而降一样
Like they dropped out of the sky.
等下
wait a sec.
这里有一行伸向树林的单个人的脚印
Got a single set of tracks heading into the woods.
什么  一个人的脚印
what, a single set?
不是凯勒的  是另一个人的
not keller's, the other guy's.
那凯勒怎么样了
so what happened to keller's?
这些脚印比前面的要深
ah, these prints are deeper.
我猜是他扛着凯勒在走
My guess is he's carrying her.
很可能他打晕了凯勒  或者...
Probably knocked her unconscious, or...
我的天
oh, god.
我跟着脚印去看看
i'm going to check it out.
也许你该先等等
maybe you should wait.
好吗  我就快到星门了
All right? I'm almost at the gate.
我先用无线电联系  请他们派一支小分队过来
I'll radio ahead, get a team here,
进行仔细搜索
Do a proper search.
听起来不错  你快去吧
that sounds good. you do that.
我会继续跟着脚印的
Meantime, I'm going after her.
麦凯?
mckay?
收到
yeah, I'm here.
我找到两个人的脚印了
i got two sets of tracks again.
她仍然还活着
She's still alive.
太好了
oh, great! that's great!
我到星门了
all right, I'm at the gate.
我先去调配支小分队过来
I'll get the search teams mobilized
然后马上和你汇合
And join you shortly.
糟糕
oh, crap!
若楠
ronon!
什么事
what?
我遇到幽灵人了
we got wraith!
人数多少
how many?
4个刚刚穿越星门
four of them just came through the gate.
其中一个正在追杀我
One of them's about to kill me!
你总算...
Oh, finally! oh...
怎么花了这么长时间
what took you so long?
不客气
oh, you're welcome.
是追踪猎人
it's a hunter.
什么
what?
幽灵追踪猎人  他们在追捕逃亡者
wraith hunter. they chase runners.
我还以为逃亡者所剩无几了
i thought runners were extremely rare.
就像宇宙的繁星一点
Like, only a few in the galaxy.
没错
that's right.
几年前  我们遇到了你  现在又来一个?
so a few years ago, we run into you, now another?
这是什么几率啊这
What are the odds of that?
其他幽灵往哪个方向去了
where'd the other wraith go?
我不知道  他们分散穿进了森林
i don't know, they spread out into the forest.
你去哪里  你去哪里  等等
where're you going? where are you going? hey! wait!
我们留下的踪迹就到此为止了
this is as far as we go on the trail.
你打算把我带到哪里去
oh! where are you taking me?
至少告诉我你叫什么
at least tell me your name.
到了之后我们会有时间谈话的
there'll be time to talk when we get there.
哪里
where?
你在干嘛
what are you doing?
若楠
ronon?
小心
watch out!
我们需要把你们的人尽快
we need to get your people
转移到安全的地方去
To a safe place as fast as possible.
为什么  发生什么了
why? what happened?
我们确定幽灵人就在这个区域
we spotted wraith in the area.
幽灵人?  来这里?
wraith? coming here?
希望不是  我们刚见到了几个
hopefully not. it's just a few of them.
他们大概是在找什么人
We think they're looking for someone else.
但我们不能冒这个险
but we don't want to take any chances.
你最近有没有看见过
have you seen anyone different
不太平常的人来到这个村庄
In the village recently?
任何...任何新来的
Any... any newcomers,
任何看上去...
Anyone that looks, uh... uh...
像这样的
Like that?
没有
no.
没时间说这个了
we don't have time for this.
这里有没有能让人们躲的地方
Is there a place your people can hide?
这个村庄附近有数不清的洞穴
there are dozens of caverns surrounding the village.
我们的祖先在那次大屠杀中就是躲在里面的
Our ancestors used them during the last culling.
好的  我们快走
good. come on, let's go.
那是什么东西
what is that thing?
解释起来太费时间
take too long to explain.
太费时间?
too long?
我们已经走了几个小时了
We've been walking for hours now.
你至少也得让我休息一下啊
can I at least rest for a bit?
不行
no.
就几分钟
just a few minutes?
休息几分钟
a few minutes to allow your team
好让你的组员接近我们?
To gain ground on us?
什么组员
what team?
你来自亚特兰蒂斯
you're from atlantis.
你是一个医生
You're a doctor.
有两个男人和你同行
There were two men traveling with you.
脚下当心
watch your step.
保持前进
Just keep going.
穿过那条峡谷
It's just past that gully,
就快要到了
You're almost there.
就这样  对  脚下小心  先生
that's it, that's it. mind your step, sir.
先生?
sir?
夫...夫人  对不起
ma... ma'am. sorry.
你有...
I...you have a...
那是很明显的胡子
That is clearly a mustache.
这是最后一个
that's the last of them.
村庄已经空了
The village is empty now.
好的  你和他们一起去  让他们呆在洞穴里
good. go with them, make sure they stay in the caverns.
并且让他们保持安静  除非有我的消息
And keep 'em quiet, make sure no one makes a sound unless you hear from me.
或者我的
or me.
好的  谢谢
all right. thank you.
我们是不是应该回星门那里去了
hey, maybe we should go back to the gate?
不  你回去吧
no, go ahead.
我要去追凯勒了
I'm going to keep tracking keller.
我看现在分头不是一个好主意
i do not think it is wise for us to split up.
我们根本不知道幽灵人在哪里
We have no idea where the wraith are
回去的路太长
it takes too long to go back.
那个逃亡者把她抓走了
That runner took her.
如果让他们走太远
We let him get too far ahead,
我们就再也找不到了
We'll never find them.
如果你想去星门的话
look, you want to go to the gate,
那你就去  我走了
Go ahead. I'm leaving.
若楠  若楠
ronon? ronon!
我...妈的
i...oh, dammit!
你不能...若楠
Would you just...ronon!
不会再逃了吧
you done trying to escape?
更多幽灵人在靠近
More wraith close by.
我们得继续前进了
We need to keep moving.
你不是村庄里的人  对吗
you're not from the village, are you?
我从没见过你
i've never noticed you,
这里几乎每个人我都认识
And I pretty much met everyone.
你是这个星球上的吗
Are you even from this planet?
是你把幽灵人引来的
you're the one who brought the wraith here.
他们在追你  为什么
They're after you. why?
我是一个逃亡者
i'm a runner.
你了解逃亡者吗
you know about runners?
和我同行的一个人
one of the men I'm traveling with,
他以前就是
He used to be one.
现在不是了?
used to be?
这不可能
That's impossible.
逃亡者不可能停止逃亡
Runners don't stop being runners.
是吗  他就能
yeah? well, this one did.
是吗  他如何做到的
yeah? well, how?
把我带到他那里去  我们就会告诉你
take me to him, and we'll tell you.
我保证
i promise.
听着  我们不需要成为敌人
Look, we don't have to be enemies.
得了吧
nice try.
喂  如果你...
hey! if you...
干嘛
what?
从这里开始  凯勒的踪迹又出现了
this is where keller's tracks start up again.
看  更小了  更浅了
look, smaller, shallower,
亚特兰蒂斯步
Atlantis tread.
这些脚印更大更深
These prints are bigger and deeper.
是逃亡者的
the runner.
凯勒的脚印不对称
keller's tracks are uneven.
她不是受伤了就是被绑了
She's either hurt or bound.
或许两者都是
Probably both.
至少这些脚印还算清楚
well, at least the tracks are clear, though.
很容易追踪  对吧
Easier to follow, right?
问题就在这儿
that's the problem.
没有一个逃亡者会如此笨
No runner is that stupid.
天马上就要黑了
it's going to be dark soon.
实际上  我们还有2小时43分钟17秒
actually, we have two hours, 43 minutes, and 17 seconds.
这星球这个时节太阳落山非常缓慢
This planet's sun currently has a very gradual angle of descent
夜晚也很短
And a very short night.
我一向特别留意下载各个星球的数据
I always make it a point to download the planetary data
凡是那些我去过的  包括那些考察项目
On every address I dial, even goodwill missions.
比如说大气情况
Yeah, things like atmospheric conditions,
土壤稠性  可用的水源什么的
Soil consistencies, available water supplies...
干嘛
what?
我只是在想  如果没有你手上的那个小玩意
just wondering how long you'd make it out here
你还能坚持多久
Without your little gadgets.
我想你会大吃一惊的
you know, I think you'd be surprised.
我的意思是  可能我并不像你们那样
You know, I mean, I may not be exactly
是一个所谓户外生活高手
What you'd call an outdoors person,
但这并不代表我不懂得体验
But that doesn't mean I don't find
人类对抗自然过程中的乐趣
The whole man vs. nature thing uninteresting.
我小时候参加过
Hell, I joined a scouting organization
一个童子军之类的组织
When I was a child.
麦穆里堡海狸捕捉团第14分队
Lodge 14 of the fort mcmurray eager beavers.
海狸
beavers?
是啊  大型啮齿动物  牙齿很大
yep. large rodent. big teeth.
能把树咬断
They use 'em to chop down trees
然后造水坝  很勤奋的
And build dams...very industrious.
我就去了几个月
I was with them for a few months
然后他们就叫我走了
Before they asked me to leave,
但我得到了指南手册
我还保存着呢  "捕捉海狸"
很珍贵的资源
Valuable resource.
所以  你会发现  在紧要关头
So, I think you'll find, in a pinch,
我绝对能自保的  非常感谢...
I handle myself very well, thank you very...
这是什么
What is it?
血
blood.
我的天
oh, my god.
不  这是幽灵人的血
no, it's wraith blood.
看这里
Here we go.
有人在这儿坐过
Someone was sitting here.
看
look.
单人的脚印
Single set of tracks...
但他们是留下那脚印  人却往这边走了
But they left the trail going that way.
你确定吗
are you sure?
脚印是往这边的
'cause the footprints keep going this way.
单人脚印
single set.
是的  我知道  但有可能他是把她背着呢
yeah, I know, but maybe he's carrying her again.
或者他们被幽灵人攻击了
Or maybe they were attacked by the wraith,
珍妮弗吓昏了
Jennifer was stunned,
然后逃亡者杀死了幽灵人
And then the runner kills the wraith
处理掉尸体
And disposes of the body,
背着珍妮弗继续走
And then carries jennifer on up the trail.
看这些脚印多深
Look how deep these tracks are.
我说我们应该走这边
I say we follow these.
我说的吧  逃亡者没有那么笨
like I said, no runner is that stupid.
现在怎么办
what now?
我们上去
we go up.
上去?  怎么上  你有绳子吗
up? how? do you have a rope?
不需要绳子
no need for ropes.
我们刚才...
did we just...
你是怎么做到的
How did we do that?
回来后  我在一个星球上待过
i was on a planet a while back.
那儿全是高科技
Lots of technology.
从当地人那儿弄来了这个
Got this from one of the locals.
几乎一接触我的皮肤就吸上去了
Barely put it on my arm before it fused to my skin.
从那时起  只要绿灯亮时我按这儿
since then, if I hit this light when it's green,
我就能"幻影移形"了
I can disappear, move around from place to place.
空间转移
teleportation.
怪不得你能那么快把我从村里弄出来
That's how you got me out of the village so fast.
只能短距离传送
i can only go short distances.
下一跳之前
It needs time to recharge
就得充电
Between jumps,
尤其还带这个人
Especially when I take someone with me.
但这样幽灵人总追不上我的
But it's helped me stay ahead of the wraith.
我想也是
i imagine so.
麦凯
mckay!
该死
Dammit.
你究竟在干嘛
what the hell were you doing?
没看到吗
at the moment?
杀幽灵人呢!
Killing wraith!
那你停下来干什么
what are you stopping for?
我鞋子里有石头  我早说了
i had a stone in my boot, I told you.
你没说
no, you didn't.
我说了!  我说"等会儿
i did! I said "wait up,
我鞋子里进了石头"
I got a stone in my boot."
你每浪费一秒
every second you lag behind
我追踪那人就越难
Makes it that much harder for me to track this guy.
特别是天黑后
Especially at night.
不会的
not anymore.
我们不用再追踪痕迹了
We don't have to play mantracker now.
马上就能知道这家伙在哪儿
We're going to know exactly where this guy is...
多亏这方便的小玩意儿了
Thanks to this handy gadget.
看看这个信号
look at that signal.
他们跑的比我想象的远多了
They're even farther away than I thought.
我保证
Arantee you,
你总归需要我帮忙的
At some point, you'll need my help.
迟早的
you'll see.
总有你解决不了的问题
There'll be some problem you can't solve,
你就会来找我
Then you'll turn to me,
我及时搞定
I'll figure it out in the nick of time.
你要么说  "干的漂亮"
You'll say, "good job,"
要么不屑一顾
Or just grunt
要么拍拍我以示鼓励
Or slap me on the back harder than necessary,
总之  关键在于我们各有所长
Anyways, the point is... we both have our gifts.
你就别老觉得我多余了
So you need to stop resenting my presence here,
应该意识到我们是一条船上的
And start realizing we're on the same team,
为同一目标而奋斗  对吧
Both trying to achieve the same goal. all right?
你在听么
You listening?
我们有了跟踪器
We got the tracker.
你在听我说吗
Can you hear what I'm saying here?
你什么时候才能告诉我
when are you going to tell me
你想从我这儿得到什么
What you want from me?
某人需要你的帮助
i need you to help someone.
谁啊
who?
你无需知道
that's not important to you.
只需帮她治疗
You just need to give her medical attention.
她是谁?  你的妻子?
her? who is she, your wife?
一旦到那儿
when we get there,
我不能和你们待在一起
I won't be able to stay with you.
我在一个地方滞留的越久  那儿就越危险
The longer I'm in one place, the greater the danger.
说不定又引来一群幽灵人呢
Probably at least a dozen more wraith on the way.
踪迹到这儿就消失了
trail ends here.
他就在前方啊
well, he's dead ahead.
要么爬上峭壁
So either he climbed this thing,
要么想法子绕过去
Or he figured out how to get around it.
没有迹象表明他们绕过去了
no sign they went around.
那他们得用绳子什么的
well, so they must've had a rope or something.
不像我们
Unlike us.
我们怎么上去呢
Look, how are we going to get up there?
你刚刚不是说什么解决问题的么
you said something about solving a problem?
是啊  高科技问题  又不是攀岩问题
yeah, technological problems, not rock-climbing problems.
早料到了
thought so.
你可曾想过
have you ever thought about
摆脱那个跟踪装置吗
Trying to remove that tracking device?
想过啊
you could say that.
一些医生试过了
Had a few doctors try.
却从没成功
No luck.
我这儿有先进的医疗技术装置
i have advanced medical technology with me.
我知道
i know.
也许能帮你移除掉
so I could probably remove it.
记得我跟你说过的那个逃亡者吗
The runner I was telling you about?
其中一个医生帮他移除了跟踪装置
One of our doctors removed his tracking device.
他就再也不用逃亡了
That's how he was able to stop being a runner.
你包里有东西能移除它吗
you have something in here that can remove it?
有个扫描仪
i have a scanner.
用它可以精确定位
With that, I can pinpoint
跟踪仪的位置
The location of your tracking device,
将你麻醉后
Give you some anesthetic,
快速切个口  你就解脱了
Make a quick incision, you're free of it.
我
i...
听着  你不是说有人
look, you say there's someone
需要医疗救助吗
Who needs medical attention?
对所有人而言
It's going to be a lot safer for all of us
能甩掉幽灵人的跟踪
If we throw the wraith
再好不过了
Off your trail
在我们抵达之前
Before we get there.
好了
okay.
转过去
turn around.
如果你想
if you try anything...
回过身去
just turn around.
看到了吗
do you see it?
你看到了什么
what did you see?
你的跟踪装置
your tracking device...
和一般的不同
It's different...
更为复杂
It's much more complicated.
有许多分枝
It's branched out,
不仅融进脊椎
Fused not only to your spine,
也进入了脑干
But also your brain stem.
移除它会要了你的命
Removing it would kill you.
我很抱歉
i'm sorry.
我们得继续前进了
we need to get moving.
离天黑还有17分钟
okay. nightfall, 17 minutes,
如我所说  非常简单
But like I said, it's very brief.
就像  六月的白马城
Like, uh, whitehorse in june.
不是说你不知道
Oh, not that you have any idea
白马城是什么
What whitehorse is,
或许是六月  关于这事儿
Or june, for that matter...
这是?
what the...?
亲娘啊  你看到了吗
holy crap! did you see that thing?
这家伙真厉害
this guy is good.
简直就是职业杀手
this guy's a killer!
很好
good.
没人发现
No one found it.
发现什么
found what?
她叫西丽斯
her name is celise.
她怎么了
what happened to her?
摔下来  伤了腿
she fell, injured her leg.
我尽力清理了伤口  但是
I did my best to clean the wound, but...
感染了
it's infected.
什么时候发生的事
When did this happen?
几天前
a few days ago.
病情越发严重
when she got worse,
我便去寻找医生
I went looking for a doctor.
我们去了三个星球
We went to three different planets.
听说亚特兰蒂斯的人
I heard there were people from atlantis
在村中行医救人
Helping the village here with their sickness.
我就把她带来了
So I brought her here,
藏在这山洞里
Found this cave to hide her,
设下陷阱以防幽灵人
Set a few traps to keep the wraith
或其他什么人
Or anyone else away,
然后等你出现
Then waited for you to show up.
其实你可以直接向我求助
you know, you could've just asked for my help
用不着绑架我的
Instead of kidnapping me.
我不能冒这个险
i couldn't take that chance.
大多数人都不愿和逃亡者扯上关系
Most people don't want anything to do with runners.
她是你女儿吗
is she your daughter?
不是
no.
她住在村子里
She lived in a village
那里已经被幽灵人毁了
That was destroyed by the wraith.
我猜是你把幽灵人引过去的吧
let me guess. you brought the wraith there?
我在那儿就待了一夜
i stayed there one night.
没想到他们这么快就找到我了
I didn't think they'd find me that fast.
他们血洗了整个村庄
The culled the whole village.
西丽斯是我唯一救下来的
Celise was the only person I could save.
她的情况有多糟
how bad is she?
非常糟
very bad.
她的血压低的可怕
Her blood pressure's dangerously low.
伤口已经腐烂  就要休克了
She's septic, going into shock.
什么意思
what does that mean?
就是说伤口坏死了
it means the wound is necrotic.
得动手术清除了
I'm going to have to surgically debride it,
切除坏死组织
Cut away the dead tissue.
我要先给她注射抗生素
I'm going to start her on an i.v. antibiotic,
但她需要的
But she needs
是比这更强的药
much stronger medications than I have with me.
她病得非常非常重
She's a very, very sick girl.
她不能死
She can't die.
你不能让她死
You cannot let her die.
我会尽力而为
I'll do what I can.
我就在附近
I'll be close by.
别紧张
It's okay.
别紧张  我是来帮你的
It's okay, I'm here to help you.
我给你的腿上了点麻药
I gave you some medicine to numb your leg.
还觉得痛吗
Do you feel any pain?
好的  那就好
Good. That's good.
基里克在哪里
Where's Kiryk?
基里克
Kiryk.
原来这就是他的名字
So that's his name.
他在外面守着
He's just outside, keeping watch,
保证你的安全
making sure you're safe. okay?
那个娃娃很漂亮
That's a beautiful doll.
基里克给我做的
Kiryk made it for me.
刻薄的老基里克
Mean old Kiryk, huh?
想也知道
Go figure.
他不刻薄
He's not mean.
他只是装成那样
He just pretends to be.
我认识个和他一样的人
I know someone just like him.
信号在打圈
The signal's circling.
不管那人把她带到哪儿
Wherever he's taking her,
他们肯定到目的地了
I think they've arrived.
离天亮还有多久
How long before daybreak?
不久  可能1小时之内
Not long now. Maybe under an hour.
很快
It's pretty short.
你在干嘛  开枪啊
What are you doing? Shoot it!
不准动
Don't move.
又排除一个陷阱了
One less trap to worry about.
你这算是安慰吗
Is that supposed to be comforting?
你吓到我了
You scared me.
她怎么样了
How is she?
我尽力
I debrided the wound,
清理了伤口
cleaned it as best I could,
但她还没脱离危险  从长远来说
But she's not out of danger, not by a long shot.
她需要更强力的抗生素来支撑
She needs a much stronger antibiotic regimen,
更别提考虑皮肤移植了
Not to mention the probability of a skin graft.
我想把她带到亚特兰蒂斯
I'd like to take her to Atlantis.
我们的医务室
Our infirmary can provide her
能给她更适合的照料
with the proper care she needs.
我不能去亚特兰蒂斯
I can't go to Atlantis.
我知道
I know.
你要相信我能照顾她
You're going to have to trust me with her care.
只要你答应她一痊愈你就把她带回给我
As long as you return her to me when she's healed.
基里克你要明白
Kiryk, you have to understand something.
并没有什么能保证她脱险
There's no guarantee she's going to survive this.
她还是病得很重
She's still very sick.
即使她能活下来...
But if she survives...
不停地被幽灵人追捕
Being constantly hunted by the wraith
也不是孩子该有的生活
is no life for a child.
你明白的
You know that.
如果你真要她活下来
If you really want her to live,
你就要放她走
you need to let her go.
如果我早知道她会...
if I knew that she would--
那是什么
What is it?
基里克?
Kiryk?
发生什么事
What happened?
幽灵人打晕了你
The wraith stunned you.
还差点杀死了西丽斯
Almost killed Celise.
我弄不醒你
I couldn't revive you--
他们一定对你用了
They must've hit you with a triple dose
普通剂量的三倍
of whatever is in those stunners.
总之  我觉得我们必须离开那个山洞
Anyway, I knew we had to get away from the cave,
所以我把西丽斯带到了这里  然后再回去
So I carried Celise here, and then I went back,
把你一路拖到了这里
And literally dragged you the distance.
我告诉你  累得我够呛
Not an easy task, let me tell you.
她怎么样了
How is she?
就目前来说  还比较稳定
Stable, for the time being.
但她还是高烧不退
But... her fever is still very high.
她在这个星球待得越久
The longer she stays on this planet,
危险就越大
the greater the danger.
我来背她
I'll carry her.
我们回星门
We'll head back for the gate.
在幽灵人还对我们紧追不舍的情况下?
With the wraith closing in on us?
你觉得我们还能要走多远
How far do you think we're going to get?
总比你带她走得要远
A lot farther than you trying to carry her yourself.
好了听着
Okay, look.
我在想
I've been thinking.
我也许拿不掉跟踪仪
I may not be able to remove the tracking device,
但也许有办法让它运作不了
but there might be a way to disable it.
这机器...叫电击器
this machine... it's called a defibrillator.
它能产生强大的电流
It creates a powerful electric shock
使人的心脏恢复正常的韵律
to restore someone's heart to the proper rhythm,
所以我想
And I think,
如果我把两电极
If I can place the paddles
放在跟踪仪位置的皮肤上  来电击那么一下
on the skin directly above your tracking device,
我能让它加载过多的电量
I might be able to overload the power source.
烧坏电路
Fry the circuits.
好吧  就这么做
All right. Do it.
但是你要知道
Okay, but you should know
我可不保证能奏效
that there's no guarantees this is going to work,
同时  这还有很大的危险性
And it also carries a lot of risk.
但如果有用的话  那跟踪器就没用了
If it works, the device will be disabled.
如果我死了...还是一样
If it kills me... same thing.
幽灵人不能再追踪我了
The wraith won't be able to track me anymore.
是时候停止逃亡了
It's time to stop running.
不远了
It's not too much further.
你保证会照顾好她
Promise me you'll make sure she's cared for.
我保证
I promise.
好吧
Okay.
电荷从一个电极到另一个电极
The charge moves from one paddle to the other.
你身上的跟踪器
And your tracking device
正是在两个电极的正中间  好了吗
is going to be directly between them. okay?
好了
All right.
准备好了?
Ready?
好  我们开始了
Okay, here we go.
见鬼了
What the hell?
什么
What?
我不知道  只是...
I don't know, it just...
信号突然停了
suddenly stopped transmitting.
我们失去他们的联系了
We lost them.
快醒醒...
Come on...
你还好吗
You okay?
发生了什么
What-- what happened?
你心脏停了一会儿
I lost you for a moment.
但你还是回来了
But you're back in the land of the living.
它起作用了吗
Did it work?
我想是的
I think so.
跟踪仪不再传输信号了
The device isn't transmitting any signals.
我想我们把那鬼东西烧坏了
I think we successfully fried the sucker.
哦  不
Oh, no...
怎么了
What?
我想我们把它也烧坏了
I guess we fried that, too.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
我们不需要它了
Don't need it anymore.
事实上
Actually...
我认识个人
I know someone who would love
可能有兴趣研究这玩意儿
to inspect a gadget like that.
有什么发现没
Anything?
什么
What?
有人被拖过了这里
A body was dragged through here.
你发现了什么
You got something?
是啊  两个人曾经躺在这儿
Yeah. Two bodies laid here.
地上两个地方都被踩踏过
Ground cover's trampled in two spots.
就是说幽灵人比我们先找到他们了?
So the wraith got to them before we did?
我觉得不是
I don't think so.
我没有看到幽灵人的脚印
I don't see any wraith footprints anywhere.
那发生了什么事
Well, so what happened?
难道  他们相互杀了对方?
What, they killed each other?
没人死了
No one's dead.
至少在这里的时候没有
At least they weren't when they were here.
看  有人被拖过这里
Look. One body was dragged through here...
凯勒拖的  她的脚印
By keller-- her footprints.
所以是她杀了他
So she killed him.
在弄坏他的跟踪器的时候
Probably in the process of disabling his tracking device.
没有  她没杀他
Nah. She didn't kill him.
他那个时候昏过去了
He was unconscious.
他的脚印在她旁边
His footprints, side-by-side with hers,
朝那边走了
Leaving the clearing that way.
什么  她把昏迷的他拽到这里来
so, what, she brought him here unconscious,
救醒他  然后一起离开?
Revived him, and they left together?
照理是这样
looks like it.
慢着  你说这里有两个人躺着的痕迹
hey. wait a second. you said there were two bodies.
难道她在这里小憩片刻了吗
So, what, she took a nap?
不  另一个人的痕迹太小了  不是keller
no. too small for keller.
我猜  还有别的人跟他们在一起
My guess is someone else is with them.
或许是个孩子
Probably a child.
但没有留下脚印吗
but no footprints?
没有
no.
她是被背着过来的
She was carried here.
她?  你怎么知道她是个女孩
she? how could you possibly know the kid was a girl
幽灵人飞船
darts.
看来我们并不是唯一知道
looks like we're not the only ones
他的追踪信号消失了的人
Who noticed his signal died.
现在可以用上空间转移装置了
could sure use that teleportation device now.
下面不远处有一条小路下去
there's a path down not too far from here.
你在这等着
Stay here.
我下去看看  那还安不安全
I'll check to make sure it's still safe.
若楠  若楠  慢着
ronon! ronon, wait!
珍妮弗
jennifer!
叫他停手
make him stop!
什么  为何啊
what? why?
若楠  快停手
ronon, please! stop!
帮帮我  抱起她
help me. grab her!
停手
stop!
听着  他只是想我去救那小女孩
listen, he just wanted me to help the little girl.
她病了
She's sick!
性命垂危
She's dying.
若楠  我们要带她回亚特兰蒂斯
We need to get her back to atlantis. ronon!
拜托了
Please?
珍妮弗  那...那...
jennifer, the...the...
她的伤口又裂开了
her sutures have torn.
得重新缝合一下才能移动她
I need to restitch her before we can move her.
幽灵人到处追捕你
you got wraith looking for you.
我知道
i know.
听着  与其打个你死我活
listen, you stand a better chance
倒不如团结一致  对抗外敌
Fighting them together than fighting each other.
我是说  虽然这样突围的几率
I mean, obviously the odds of actually winning
也是微乎其微  但是
Are still ridiculously low, but...
说这话于事无补
not helping.
我要去...
I'm going to go...
他说得对
he's right.
幽灵人很快就蜂拥而至
This place is going to be swarming with wraith.
团结就是力量
it's better off if we work together.
好了  包扎好了
all right, she's ready.
走吧
let's go.
幽灵人
wraith!
妈的
oh, crap.
若楠
ronon!
开枪啊
shoot him!
这就来
i will!
什么时候学会这些招数的
where'd you learn to fight like that?
他教了我几招格斗技
uh... been taking a few sparring lessons.
我们得转移了
we need to move.
我尝试稳定她的病情
i tried to stabilize her,
但是她必须要接受更强的药物治疗
But she needs stronger medication.
你要她帮你救人
you know, you could've just asked
你尽管开口就好了
For her assistance
也不至于要掳走她
As opposed to kidnapping her.
罗德尼  他知道的了
he knows, rodney.
有样东西要给你
Here, I got you something.
是个空间转移装置
It's a kind of teleportation device.
空间转移?  真的吗
teleportation? really?
是的  的确如此
well, it was, anyway.
不过我弄坏了
I kind of broke it.
她是你的家人吗
is she family?
我把幽灵人引到她的村子
i brought the wraith to her village.
她是唯一的幸存者
She's the sole survivor.
四处逃亡  不容易啊
it's not easy... living with that.
别担心
don't worry.
我们会帮助你们两个
We're going to get you out of this.
结束逃亡生涯的
Both of you.
下面有6个幽灵人
i count six wraith on the ground.
肉眼见到有6个没错
six that we can see.
可能还有些隐藏在丛林之中
Probably more in the surrounding woods.
要冒险一搏吗  杀出重围?
want to make a run for it? shoot our way through?
只要我们一开火  他们的飞船就会接收到信息
the ships will be alerted as soon as the shooting starts.
我们在拨号前就被抓了
We'll be culled before we can even dial.
无论如何  也要放手一搏
just going to have to take our chances.
你修好了
you fixed it!
我才不会修理  顶多弄一下
i don't know about "fixed," more of a patch.
这东西复杂得很
It's incredibly complicated technology.
我还不知道这能不能...喂
I'm not sure if it'll actually... hey!
你干什么
what're you doing?
我准备为突围加点胜算
i'm going to improve our chances.
别独自下去冒险啊
don't go down there by yourself.
没事的
i'll be fine.
准备进攻吧
Get ready to attack that clearing.
慢着  等一下  好吗
look, just-just-just wait a second, all right?
我不知道那东西是不是真的能用
I'm not sure if I actually fixed it.
用之前最好测试一下
You'll need to test it before you...
我猜  这该是修好了吧
I guess I did fix it.
他在星门那边
he's at the gate!
你们留着这里
stay with them.
他正在拨号
he's dialing the gate.
我们得继续前进
we've got to get a move on.
好的  让我抱她到星门那边
all right, well, we'll take her to the gate,
然后再回来
Then I'll go back,
告诉村民  这里已经安全可以回去
Tell people it's safe to return to the village.
不  不  它们飞上去了
uh, no, no, as they fly up,
你就要按这个键
You want to use that button there
射击它们
To shoot them.
射那些鸭子
shoot the ducks?
它们当然不是真的鸭子
they're not real ducks, obviously.
它们只是...假冒的
They're just, you know, for pretend...
或许她该玩别的游戏
maybe you should show her a different game.
是的  好的  这里
yeah. yeah, sure. here.
你的小病人怎么了
well, how's our little patient?
情况不错
oh, much better.
她很勇敢
She's a heck of a fighter.
他有烦着你吗
is he bothering you?
有的话  我可以强制他离开
Because I can have him removed. forcibly.
真的吗
really?
他开玩笑的
yeah. he's kidding.
我跟985星球中的一户人家谈过
i talked to one of the families on 985...
就是我们拜访过的那个女士的家
The woman's home we visited?
她很乐意收留西丽斯
She'd love to have celise come live with them.
太好了
that's great.
我还会再见到基里克吗
will I see kiryk again?
小甜心  我也不知道
i don't know, sweetheart.
我们也在找他
we're still looking for him.
用心留意他的行踪
Keeping our eyes and ears open.
我有样东西要给你
hey, I brought you something.
你在树林里丢下的
I think you dropped this in the woods...
娃娃
my doll.
怎么了
what?
好的
okay...
是这样的
Here's the thing.
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
我要知道你的企图
And, uh, I need to know your intentions.
企图?
intentions?
对珍妮弗的企图
with jennifer?
我没有任何企图
i don't have any intentions.
好吧
Okay.
很好
Good.
慢着
wait.
你说企图  是什么意思
what do you mean by "intentions?"
我是说  你是不是对她有...
i mean, are you interested in her in a...
好...感
Romantic... fashion?
没有
no.
很好
good.
慢着
wait.
怎么了
what?
或许我是
maybe I do.
有...企图
Have... intentions.
你有什么企图吗
do you have intentions?
当然了  所以我才来问你
yes, well, of course I do. that's why I was asking you.
那我们要怎么做
so what are we going to do about it?
我不知道
i don't know.
你大概是想我退出竞争吧
I won't fight you for her, if that's what you're thinking.
好极了
great!
我才不会把她拱手相让
i'm not going to step aside, either.
那...我们还是交由她去决定
So... we're just going to have to let her decide.
好的
okay.
希望...强者能夺得芳心
so... may the best man win.